Guide to the Andrew Jackson Davis Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Andrew Jackson Davis papers
1848-1929
1848-1881
MS 677
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
Letters from Andrew Jackson Davis, author and spiritualist to William Green, Jr., his benefactor. The letters deal with personal, family, and financial matters as well as Davis' work with spiritualism and healing.
Davis, Andrew Jackson, 1826-1910
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Esther A. Tiffany, 1973.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Andrew Jackson Davis: spiritualist; ran a "clairvoyant clinic" in Poughkeepsie; from 1845 on turned to writing and lecturing; practiced both mesmerism and spiritualism.
Scope and Contents
Letters from Andrew Jackson Davis, author and spiritualist to William Green, Jr., his benefactor. The letters deal with personal, family, and financial matters as well as Davis' work with spiritualism and healing.
Popular culture; Spiritualism; Authors; Clergy; Davis, Andrew Jackson, 1826-1910; Green, William
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  Letters, 1848-1881, from Andrew Jackson Davis (1826-1910) to William Green, Jr. The letters deal with personal, family and financial matters, as well as Davis' theories on and work with spiritualism and healing.
  - Letter from William Green, Jr. to his wife relating to Davis, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters to William Green, Jr.
    - 1848-1849 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1851 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1852 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1853 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1854 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1855 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1856 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1857 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1858 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1859 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1870-1872 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1873 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1874 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1875 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1876-1879 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1880 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1881 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Tiffany, Nina Moore: "Letters of Andrew Jackson Davis to William Green, Jr.", 1929 (Box 1, Folder 21)